

## RAMESH RAJU BHUPATHIRAJU

Personal Information:

**Gender:** Male

**DOB**: 15-07-1975

Mobile: 7204512544

Email: rameshrajuartist @gmail.com

Spoken languages:

English, Telugu, Kannada

Marital Status: Married

Nationality: Indian

Postal Address: Hullahalli village, Nanjangudu Taluk, Mysore District, Karnataka

**PIN:** 571314

**Summary:** 

I have professional experience in Tutoring, Academic Writing, Corporate Video Script Writing, Content Writing, Data Entry, Storyboarding, Screenplay Scriptwriting, Character sketching, Website readable content, User help text for Mobile/PC/Online games, User manuals of Electronic products, HR Manuals, News/Subject Articles on various topics, and Proofreading. I can teach English to the students of Middle School and High School, PUC/Intermediate, Degree, and Engineering, etc. Besides communicating with clients/customers via Chatbots, e-mail, I can also serve as the customer care executive efficiently.

Skills:

Academic Writing (SME) Textbook content writing

Website Content Writing Resume/CV Writing

Technical Content Writing Internet browsing

Proofreading E-mail/Chatbot communication

Screenplay script writing Product description/ review writing

Article writing High speed typing

Data Entry MS Word, MS Excel, PowerPoint

Manual Storyboarding Tutoring

Comic Book drawing Lesson Plan writing (international)

Corporate Video Script writing Caricature

 $English \longleftrightarrow Telugu\ Translation,\ Transliteration$ 

**Ethics:** 

I believe that - Work is worship; Known is a drop, unknown is an ocean; Everyone is a learner; Honesty is the best policy; Knowledge is power, Education is life; Fear on the Lord, is the beginning of knowledge; You reap what you sow

## Website Links:

Linkedin:

https://www.linkedin.c om/in/rameshrajubhupathiraju-8735441a/

Naukri:

https://www.naukri.co m/mnjuser/profile?id= &orgn=homepage

## **Work Experience**

Role, Work place

Tenure

Currently working as an English Teacher for the higher classes in Rotary School at Nanjangudu Teaching Spoken English and Academic syllabus for the students

Worked on freelance projects online for Samvridhi Info Media Technologies, Bangalore Worked on Corporate Video Scripts (or explainer videos)

Tutor, Online, Self Employed 2015-2021 Worked as a tutor and took Spoken English online by Zoom App for higher class students. (March, April, May, June)

Subject Matter Expert, Remote at Infinizi Consultancy, 2021, June, July New Delhi

Produced Academic papers (Ph.D. thesis) on various topics related to English, Biology, Health and Management

Content/Script writer at 7Seas Entertainment Ltd, 2006-2014
Hyderabad
Produced user help texts for more than 400 mobile/online/PC games

Worked on screenplay script of an animated film Produced website text content for game portals

Data Entry Operator, Gokaraju Institute of 2005 Engineering & Technology , Hyderabad Maintained thousands of records of engineering students

Data Preparation Officer, Veeravasaram PHC, 2004 Government of AP

Maintained thousands of records of families living in surrounding villages of a taluk. west Godavari district. Andhra Pradesh

Teacher at Sarada Residential School, Bhimavaram 1994-1997;

1998-2003; 2015

Taught English, Maths, Science & Social for higher class students

## **Education:**

MA- English Literature, Osmania University, 2006

B.Sc – Mathematics, Physics, Computer Science, Andhra University, 1997

Intermediate, Board of Intermediate Education, 1993

SSLC – Board of Secondary Education, 1990